

## **CONTACT INFO**

Phone: +52 81-34-16-03-85 García, Nuevo León, MEX. rolando.code@gmail.com

#### **LANGUAGE**

Spanish

**English** 

#### **EXPERTISE**

Net Framework
Dapper
EF and EF Core
Dot Net core
Dot Net 5, 6
ASP Net Core 8
MS SQL Server
GIT
Typescript
Angular

#### MORE ABOUT ME



You can visit my portfolio scanning the QR. https://bit.ly/rdom-page

# Rolando Domínguez

.NET + ANGULAR SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER/ TECH LEAD

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a software developer with 10 years of experience, who enjoys backend development with .NET technology and Angular on the client side. I love writing clean code, it's a fully creative activity and a whole art. I feel passionate when applications are built and deployed successfully in cloud environments. Creating open-source applications, that help me daily and could help others is one of my favorite hobbies.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Coherent Solutions- Full stack developer & Tech lead**

2023- Present

<u>Full stack developer and Tech Lead at WEX client.</u> **Dotnet and angular** integrations with TPA vendors, Angular migration from version 6 to 8, **MS SQL** script database enhancements with over 1,000 tables (SP, Views, functions, etc), **Micro frontend** enhancements, support to legacy systems in **VB ASP Web Forms.** As tech lead: **API Rest** designs and **architectural concepts**, **PR reviews**, tech training and **coaching** support, proof of concepts for new APIs, **user stories definitions** with PO, **production deployment** staff, technical staff recruiter.

#### **AGILE THOUGHT- Dot net Senior and consultant developer**

2021-2023

- <u>Senior software engineer at Brierley client.</u> 2021-2022 **Net framework** code maintenance. **REST API conversion** from SOAP. Code enhancements and **code reviews in GitHub. Oracle DB** scripts.
- <u>Senior software engineer at VyStar client</u>. 2022-2023. **Net core** code maintenance. **ASP Net MVC pages** refactors and maintenance. Net core **small modules migration to net 6**. Using of MS **Azure pipelines**

#### AXOSNET- Net core, Net framework and Angular Sr. developer

2019-2021

**Net framework to Net core 3.1 migration** (from scratch. Invoice verification software **API design and creation** for México, Costa Rica, Colombia, and Perú Internal tools in **Angular and AngularJS. Technical designs** for API solutions in **net framework/core** and **SQL server**. AWS **cloudwatch**, **EC2** instances, load balancers

Bind ERP- Technical and software support lead. Semi Sr. developer 2018-2019

APIs Rest and Web Services integration for Mexican invoicing. Technical staff recruiter. ASP Net and Web forms migrations to AngularJS and Typescript. Microsoft Azure app services settings and deployments

#### Bind ERP – Jr. dot Net Framework and AngularJS developer

2015-2018

**SQL server** production DB management. Computer building and maintenance, local network configuration. Support app creation with **AngularJS** with **Typescript** and **Net Framework.** 

## **ACADEMIC BACKGROUND**

Master's degree in Information Technology Engineering

2016-2018

School of mechanical and electrical engineering. UANL.

**Computer Science degree** 

2010-2015

School of Physics and Mathematics UANL

## **CERTIFICATES**

- Using SOLID principles to Write Better Code
- Creating professional web APIs with .NET 6
- Software Engineering 101: Use Software Engineering to Plan and Build Amazing Software + Learn SCRUM Framework!

# GitHub projects

https://github.com/orgs/OpenSourceRvProjects/repositories https://github.com/orgs/My-Proffesional-Portfolio/repositories